Finding Aid for East Quad Memory Project (University of Michigan) records, 1977-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
East Quad Memory Project (University of Michigan) records 1977-2012
University of Michigan. East Quad Memory Project
.1 linear feet and 5.72 GB
2012064 Bimu 2
A community history project intended to record memories and information about East Quad, the traditional home of Residential College, before the structure underwent significant renovations in the summer of 2012. The collection includes video footage and email correspondence of current and former residents, administrators, faculty, and staff sharing stories about life in East Quad as well as a documentary video, images of murals, and a cookbook from the Halfway Inn café.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by East Quad Memory Project (donor no. 10773 ) in April 2012.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The East Quad Memory Project was organized by Residential College (RC) student Rosie Levine in the spring of 2012 with support from college administration. An outgrowth from a class assignment, the East Quad Memory Project's goal was to record information and personal memories about RC's traditional home before extensive renovations were undertaken in the summer of 2012. Current and former staff, administrators, professors, and residents contributed stories and memories to the project via email and video-recorded talks at the East Quadapalooza event held on March 30, 2012. Participants also provided historical records dating back to the late 1970s, which included event materials, cook book, and a Residential College fortieth anniversary video created in 2007.
The East Quad Memory Project records preserves the memories of East Quad as shared by current and former Residential College students, staff and administrators. The collection provides documents the impact of the College's unique environment on students and will furthermore be of use to those interested in the social life and customs of University of Michigan students. The record group consists of two series: East Quadapalooza and Historical Records.
Subjects:
East Quadrangle (University of Michigan); East Quad Memory Project.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Residential College.; University of Michigan. Student housing.; University of Michigan. Students--Social life and customs.; East Quadapalooza.; Education--Michigan.
- East Quadapalooza
  The East Quadapalooza series includes promotional materials and video footage from East Quadapalooza, an event organized by Rosie Levine and held in the East Quad's Greene Lounge from 5-8 p.m. on March 30, 2012. Former and current professors, administrators, staff, and residents shared memories of life in East Quad over the years, many of which were captured on digital video. The evening concluded with a music performance at the Halfway Inn.
  - Concert ticket, 2012 (Box 1)
  - Promotional poster, 2012
  - Video footage of individuals sharing stories about East Quad, 2012 (10 files)
- Historical Records
  The Historical Records series is comprised of materials collected over the course of the project. These include email correspondence between Rosie Levine and individuals who sought to share memories of East Quad, event fliers and a newsletter from the 1980s, a cookbook from the Halfway Inn café, and a catalog and images of East Quad's murals.
  - Catalog of murals in East Quad (with images), 2012
  - Email correspondence: memories of East Quad, 2012
  - Hayden Notes (newsletter), ca. 1980 (Box 1)
  - Recipes from the Halfway Inn: cookbook, 1978
  - Residential College Commencement Program, 2012 (Box 1)
  - Women's Issues symposia fliers, ca. 1980-1985 (Box 1)
  - Self Portraits of the Residential College (fortieth anniversary documentary), 2007